(upbeat music)
- Hello everyone, welcome
back to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
- And I'm Erica.
- And where are we going today, Erica?
- To the pharmacy.
- All right, to the pharmacy or drugstore?
- Yes.
- Or also in British English,
sometimes people say the chemist.
- That's right.
- So as you know, at
the pharmacy you get
medicine, but there are
certain vocabulary words
that are related to this
place that we need to learn.
- That's right, so we're gonna learn
some vocabulary about medicine.
- And also some interesting phrases.
So before we listen to the dialogue,
let's take a look at vocabulary preview.
- Very cabaret-y preview.
- We're going to look at two words
today that you'll hear in the dialogue.
And the first one, milligrams.
- Milligrams.
- Also the abbreviation for this is mg.
- That's right, okay.
So a milligram is a hundredth of a gram.
So there are 100 milligrams in a gram.
- Exactly, and it's very common
to be used with medicine, right?
- Exactly.
- By medicine in milligrams.
Okay, and what's our next word?
- Price check.
- A price check.
- Okay, so at the pharmacy
or at the supermarket,
sometimes the cashier
will ask for a price check.
- And that is the action of
checking to find out the price.
- Okay, so a price check.
With this, I think we're ready now to
listen to our dialogue for the first time,
and let's see what our shopper
is buying at the pharmacy.
(upbeat music)
- Hello, sir.
How can I help you?
- Yes, I need this prescription, please.
- Let's see, okay.
So 50 milligrams of Prozac, would
you prefer this in capsule or tablet?
- Capsules are right.
- Okay, you should take
one capsule three times a day.
Be sure not to take it on an empty stomach
and also don't ever mix it with alcohol.
- Yes, I know.
It's not the first time I'm taking this.
Don't worry, I've won't overdose.
- Okay, anything else I can get you?
- Oh, yes, I almost forgot.
Can I also get some eye
drops and some condoms?
- Sure.
- Darn condoms aren't
registered in our system.
- Oh, well, that's okay.
I'll get some later, thanks.
Really, it's no problem.
- Just hang on there a sec.
Can I get a price check on fun
times, ripped condoms, please?
- Oh.
(upbeat music)
- Oh, no, how embarrassing.
A little bit embarrassing that she asked
for a price check on these condoms, right?
- Yeah, but you know what?
It seems like every time you have
to buy something embarrassing
at the farm estate, there's
a million people watching it.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- It never fails.
- Yeah.
- Well, let's take a look
at some of those words
that we were talking about related
to medicine in language takeaway.
- Language takeaway.
All right, well, the first
word, a prescription.
- Prescription.
- All right, so what is a prescription?
- Well, a prescription is a note from your
doctor explaining what medicine you need.
So this note from your doctor is
necessary to buy that medicine, right?
- Exactly.
- Okay, prescription.
Well, this shopper was getting some medicine
and, well, the chemist or the pharmacist
asked if he wanted it
in capsules or tablets.
- So let's look at those
two words, a capsule.
- Capsule.
- Now, a capsule is
like a small tube, right?
- Yeah, it's a form of a pill.
And it's shaped like a tube
with the medicine inside.
And it's covered in plastic, right?
- Exactly.
- Now, you swallow the capsule.
- Yeah.
- And the tablet is like a
pill that is round and flat.
- Okay, so tablet and capsule,
both are the same thing
basically, but just
different presentations.
- Different shapes.
- Yeah.
- It's easier maybe for some
people to swallow a capsule.
- You think so?
- I don't know, I think so.
- Well, because sometimes at tablets
are a little bit like big circles
and it's hard to swallow.
- Yeah.
- I guess, and I guess
capsules are smoother.
- Yeah, exactly.
- But we're not pharmacists.
So let's move on and focus on the
language, which is what we do know about.
So the pharmacists warned the patient
not to take too much medicine, right?
- Mm-hmm.
- Because he might overdose.
- Overdose.
- Okay, so to overdose, like you said,
is to take too much medicine
and get really sick or even die.
- So if you overdose on medicine, it
could be bad for you instead of good.
- Well, obviously very bad.
- And what about our last word for today?
- Well, the shopper also
asked for some eye drops.
- Eyedrops.
- So this is medicine for your eyes.
- Yeah, usually liquid, like
water that you put in your eyes.
- Okay.
So I think now with this
medicine language clear,
we can listen to our dialogue again,
but it's gonna be slowed down a little bit.
- That'll help us understand
these phrases just a little bit better.
(upbeat music)
- Hello, sir.
How can I help you?
- Yes, I need this prescription, please.
- Let's see.
Okay, so 50 milligrams of Prozac.
Would you prefer this in capsule or tablet?
- Capsules are fine.
Okay, you should take one
capsule three times a day.
Be sure not to take it on an empty stomach,
and also don't ever mix it with alcohol.
- Ha ha, yes, I know.
It's not the first time I'm taking this.
Don't worry, I won't overdose.
- Okay, anything else I can get you?
- Oh, yes, I almost forgot.
Can I get some eye drops and some condoms?
- Sure, darn condoms aren't
registered in our system.
- Oh, well, that's okay.
I'll get some later, thanks.
Really, it's no problem.
- Just hang on there, a sec.
Can I get a price check on fun
times, ribbed condoms, please?
(upbeat music)
- Okay, so now it's
time for us to take a look
at some of the phrases that we saw
in this dialogue in putting it together.
Putting it together.
We're gonna look at two
phrases here, and we're gonna
see how we can use
them in different situations.
The pharmacist warned, be sure
not to take it on an empty stomach.
- Okay, so be sure not to.
- Be sure not to.
So what does he mean by this?
- He just means don't do this.
- Okay, so don't take the
medicine without eating.
- We can mix it up a little bit.
Why don't we listen to some examples of how
we can use this in different situations?
- Example one.
Be sure not to leave your bike outsider.
It will be stolen.
Example two.
Be sure not to forget your umbrella.
It's raining today.
Example three.
I told him to be sure not to
do anything stupid, but he did.
- So Marco, why should we say
be sure not to instead of don't?
- I think don't is sounds
more like an order.
- Okay.
- I'm very direct.
Maybe be sure not to as a little
bit softer, a little bit more friendly.
So be sure not to.
Now for our last phrase.
So the pharmacist in the
end wanted to check for
the price and he said,
just hang on there a sec.
- So that's interesting.
Hang on.
- Hang on.
- Well, hang on.
What does he mean by hang on?
- He means wait, wait.
It's a informal way of saying wait.
- Exactly.
It's also a little bit more
friendly than just saying wait.
- Right, exactly.
And we can change
the time a little bit, right?
- Yeah, so you can say hang on a second.
- Or hang on a moment.
- Hang on a minute.
- All right.
- What about hang on an hour?
- Well, maybe if you're
telling someone to wait
for an hour, just hang on there
for an hour, I'll be there soon.
- Yeah, but I guess it's more common.
Hang on a minute.
- Right, maybe for shorter periods of time.
Okay, so with these phrases,
I think now we can use them
in different circumstances,
obviously, not only in the pharmacy.
- Yeah.
- And well, let's listen to
our dialogue for the last time.
(upbeat music)
- Hello, sir.
How can I help you?
- Yes, I need this prescription, please.
- Let's see.
Okay, so 50 milligrams of Prozac,
would you prefer this in capsule or tablet?
- Capsules are right.
- Okay, you should take
one capsule three times a day.
Be sure not to take it on an empty stomach
and also don't ever mix it with alcohol.
- Yes, I know.
It's not the first time I'm taking this.
Don't worry, I've won't overdose.
- Okay, anything else I can get you?
- Oh, yes, I almost forgot.
Can I also get some eye
drops and some condoms?
- Sure.
- Darn condoms aren't
registered in our system.
- Oh, well, that's okay.
I'll get some later, thanks.
Really, it's no problem.
- Just hang on there a sec.
(beep)
- Can I get a price check on fun
times ripped condoms, please?
- Oh.
(upbeat music)
- Okay, so with medicine, an
interesting thing comes up, right?
- That's right, a lot of people
think that you eat medicine.
- Okay, or drink medicine?
- Yeah, but in English,
you always take medicine.
- Always take medicine.
- Yeah, so you never can say,
oh, I ate my medicine yesterday.
It always has to be, I took my medicine.
- Okay, you take the capsules.
- Exactly, or take the tablets.
- All right, so you take medicine.
Now, an interesting
thing in the United States,
for example, it's very hard to get
medicine without a prescription.
- That's right, so we always
talk about prescription medicine
and OTC medicine or
over the counter medicine.
- So over the counter medicine is,
is medicine you can just buy without
that prescription or note from your doctor?
- Okay, so for example,
if you have a headache,
you can go to the
pharmacy and buy aspirin.
- Yeah, and that's over
the counter medicine.
- But prescription medicine, you
can't get it without the doctor's note.
- Yes, and like you said in America,
you almost have to have a
prescription for everything.
- Which is strange because
people can overdose on aspirin.
So tell us how medicine and pharmacies work
in your countries, and also if
you have questions or comments,
our website englishpod.com is
always open and ready for you.
- Well, thanks for downloading this lesson,
you guys, and until next time, goodbye.
(upbeat music)